Dilip Singh

fullStack webDeveloper



GITHUB: bit.ly/devDilip

LINKEDIN:bit.ly/linkDilip

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGY:

Javascript(ES6) React / redux NodeJS HTML5

CSS3 Express

REST APIs

Postares SQL

Sequelize

Bootstrap

Material UI

Git, Github, CMD

Docker

Jest

TypeScript

BUSINESS:

UX UI Design Wireframing DigitalMarketing GoogleAnalytics FB Ads Google Ads

CONTACT

User Research

dilip.singh@iiml.org 0633030215 Rotterdam **Visa** -'TWV niet vereist'

PROFILE

After working for more than 4 years solving Business challenges, I completed accelerated boot-camp to switch career to align with my enthusiasm for technology. Now, my focus is to use that knowledge to make useful and high quality applications that help solve problems. I am looking for a role as web developer for a company that provides a mix of challenge and opportunity. I am a conceptual thinker with ability to break down a complex problem. This belief was helped by me **winning the HERE Technologies Hackathon** held in Eindhoven in June 2019 where we came up with winning solution for a real world problem

WORK EXPERIENCE

Codaisseur - Full stack Developer Trainee

Invoice/Warranty manager

A full stack application that is an online Warranty management application to keep your appliance Invoices/warranties safe and get custom notifications about their expiration using React, Express, Postgres, REST API, Bootstrap, nodemailer, Docker, JWT **LabBook**

A Full stack application to help people working in a Laboratory. User can keep track of experiments progress and record keeping also, with an option to note ideas and a todo list in a separate section. Built using React, Express, Material UI, REST APIs

Ticket swapping platform

An online platform where user can create account to create events, add tickets and comments. It also uses an algorithm to check the risk per ticket. Built using React, Express, Postgres, REST API, Bootstrap, Docker, JWT

Times Internet - Project Manager

September 2015 - September 2018

- Defined user journey for OTT content App through GoogleAnalytics
- Improved conversion rate (purchase/visit) by 50% through improvements to design and better definition of customer journey

ICICI Bank - Wealth Manager

February 2015 - February 2017

• Gathering financial requirements and coming up with asset allocation plan.

Generated highest revenue for 2 consecutive quarters for the bank in North Zone

Newgen Software - Business Analyst

December 2013 - February 2015

• Successfully identified business need through requirements gathering and helping generate additional revenue for the company and a useful feature for the client

EDUCATION

CODAISSEUR BOOTCAMP

Full-stack Web development course following AGILE Methodology (Jan - Mar 2020)

IIM LUCKNOW

Masters in Business Administration (June 2011 - Feb 2013)

PEC, CHANDIGARH

Bachelors in Computer Science Engineering (June 2006 - June 2010)